# Bill Than

#### Bachelor of Information Candidate | https://www.billthan.ca

I have over 4+ years of coding experience and 2+ years of User Experience design. My past experiences make me an exceptional candidate as a front-end developer. My research interests lie in Human-Centered Data Science (HCDS) and Human Computer Interaction (HCI).

# **Professional Experience**

# **NORMERICA Incorporated**

Software Testing Intern | January 2020 - March 2020

- Re-structured 10 years worth of accounting data for migration
- Verified 10 years worth of data in new system
- Revealed at least 50+ fatal faults / errors in SQL server
- Improved server efficiency with careful documentation

#### City of Toronto

Aquatic In-Charge & Trainer | June 2018 - present

- Restructured aquatic trainings to adhere to COVID-19 procedures
- Increased aquatic staff efficiency with effective training materials
- Confidently lead and directed swim instructors in aquatic programs
- Improved workplace efficiency with careful official documentation

# **Personal Projects**

#### BigWeather (Java, Windows)

Interactive Windows Weather Statistical Analysis tool

- Securely handled diverse API and key encryption in Java
- Efficiently deserialize raw JSON/XML metadata
- Used HCI principles to facilitate easy-to use GUI

#### Hackintosh Development (HP G1 800, XPS 9500)

Open source, EFIs for running macOS on non-Apple devices

- Maintain 50+ kernels, driver files, and config.plist
- Rigorously tested each peripheral to ensure driver compatibility
- Maintain 40+ drivers for stability

#### Natural Nails and Spa Website (HTML, CSS, .js)

https://www.naturalnailsspa.ca

- Redesigned website every year since 2015
- Monthly website maintenance
- Monthly SEO reports for client

# Education

### **University of Toronto**

Bachelor of Information (BI)

2018-2022

#### **University of Toronto**

Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Mathematics, Computer Science, and Education 2018-2020

#### Achievements

University of Toronto \$5000 Scholarship (2020)

Ontario Student \$5000 Grant (2020)

# Human Centered Design Skills

User Research

Prototyping

Agile/Iterative Design

User Journey Mapping

Usability Testing

# Technical Skills

Programming Languages

python Java

Kotlin JSON/XML

SQL C/C++

RStudio HTML5/CSS3

JavaScript

<u>Human Centered Design Tools</u>

Figma Adobe CC LaTeX markdown

BALSAMIQ